School of Medicine Records UA010
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
School of Medicine Records
1882 -- 2017
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
School of Medicine
Admissions Committee (School of Medicine Faculty)
Basic Science Appointments and Promotions Committee (School of Medicine Faculty)
Clinical Faculty Appointments and Promotions Committee (School of Medicine Faculty)
Committee on Committees (School of Medicine Faculty)
Curriculum Committee (School of Medicine Faculty)
Executive Council Committee (School of Medicine Faculty)
Faculty Grievance Committee (School of Medicine Faculty)
Scientific Affairs Committee (School of Medicine Faculty)
Student Evaluation and Promotion Committee (School of Medicine Faculty)
UA010
61.6 Linear Feet 54 boxes
2 Artifact(s)
2 Digital Object(s)
This collection contains records of the Tufts University School of Medicine.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the School of Medicine, 2003-2017.
Arrangement
This collection is organized in five series: Subject files; Office of the Dean, Subject Files; Faculty meeting and committee minutes; Photographs, lectures and examination materials; and Unprocessed accessions.
Biographical / Historical
The Tufts University School of Medicine was voted into existence by the Trustees on April 22, 1893. It was formed by the secession of seven faculty from the College of Physicians and Surgeons in Boston, a school which was formed in 1880. These "original seven" faculty members successfully lobbied to establish a medical school under the auspices of Tufts College.
The "original seven" first faculty of the Medical School were William Chipman, Henry W. Dudley, Walter L. Hall, John W. Johnson, Albert Nott, Charles P. Thayer, and Frank Wheatley. All had been members of the College of Physicians and Surgeons, but had been dissatisfied with the operations of that institution since it opened in 1880.They believed that in order to raise the standards of the school and provide for the necessary laboratory and clinical work, the school should affiliate with a college or university. President Capen was sympathetic to the idea of Tufts expanding into the realm of medical education, leading the group to concentrate their efforts on affiliation with Tufts.
The new school, which was designated the Medical School of Tufts College, opened its doors in October 1893 with a student body of eighty students. The school was, from the very beginning, coeducational, and of the twenty-two students who graduated that first year, eight were women.
The Medical School was initially located on three floors of a building at 188 Boylston Street in Boston, now the site of the Four Seasons Hotel. The building, which had formerly served as the home of the College of Physicians and Surgeons, was owned by Tufts as an investment property, and was taken for use of the Medical School upon its formation. As enrollment increased rapidly in the first years of the school's operation, the school acquired additional facilities for use in the area. By 1897 the school's growth forced it to seek a new facility. A renovated Baptist church on Shawmut Avenue became the school's new home, but the establishment of the Dental School in 1899 meant that another move was necessary. This time a building was constructed to house both schools on Huntington Avenue, which served as the Medical School's home until 1949, when it moved to its current location on Harrison Avenue in downtown Boston.
By 1905, the Medical School was the largest such school in New England, with a faculty of 105 and 403 students. While enrollments continued to climb, growth of the school was hindered by the lack of any substantial endowment and the failure to obtain a hospital for exclusive use of the school's clinical training needs.
In the first decades of the Medical School's existence there was ongoing concern about admission requirements and the implications these held for the quality of medical education and graduates of the program. Initially, a high school degree from an approved school, or examination in high school subjects was required for admission. Many felt this to be too lax, but others were hesitant to require a full college degree for admission, believing that this would put an unnecessary financial and time burden on students. However, as the American Medical Association criteria for ranking medical schools continued to be revised, admissions standards were gradually increased to a bachelor's degree by the 1932-33 academic year.
In 1929 an alliance was formed between Boston Dispensary, the Floating Hospital for Infants and Children, and the medical and dental schools, constituting the basis for the formation of the New England Medical Center (NEMC) in 1930.This served as the impetus for the medical and dental schools to move from the Huntington Avenue location to downtown Boston. However, before this could take place it was necessary to raise funds to construct a new facility, a task which was made all the more challenging in that it was undertaken in the depression years of the 1930s.
During World War II, the Medical School went on a full-year, accelerated academic calendar to meet the increased wartime demand for medical personnel. Plans continued to go ahead for construction of a new facility downtown, and the move was accomplished in 1949.This move signified the realization of the school's long-term goal of providing close affiliation with a hospital facility for its students.
Expanding curricular programs and departments to keep apace with the growing medical field placed ongoing strains on the finances of the Medical School. With the majority of income being generated by tuition revenues, efforts were intensified starting in the 1950s to seek additional public and private grant funding for projects and to drastically increase the school's endowment. Faculty were successful in obtaining funding from sources such as the Ford Foundation, the National Public Health Service, and the National Cancer Institute. In 1975-76, Professor William B. Schwartz, chair of the Department of Medicine, became the first holder of the Vannevar Bush University Professorship, the first endowed professorship in the university's history.
For much of its history, the Medical School has drawn its student body largely from the New England states. Since the 1950s this has gradually changed, with slightly less than half of entering students in 1999 coming from the six New England states.
Custodial History
Part of this material was collected by Russell Miller in preparation for writing "Light on the Hill," his history of Tufts University. These materials were arranged by subject, and no attempt was made to recreate original order. Material relating to administering the collection was removed to the documentation files of the collection in the archives.
The Office of the Dean, Subject Files were accessioned prior to the reopening of the archives in 1997. The majority of the material seems to originate from the office of the dean of the medical school, and were grouped into subject files in alphabetical order. In processing this series, items that were out of order were put back into their proper place in the alphabetical range.
Medical school publications were removed from this collection and placed in the appropriate publication collection.
Scope and Contents
The School of Medicine Records consist primarily of correspondence. Other materials include memos and files from the office of the Dean; faculty meeting and committee minutes; and photographs, lectures, and examination materials. The unprocessed accessions contain programs, bulletins and catalogs. A large portion of the collection contains files from the Tufts Comprehensive Community Action Program (TCCHAP). There are two folders containing the few photos of early faculty. The entire collection is arranged by subject.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Faculty; Alumni and Alumni Relations; Advancement; Facilities; Research and Research Administration
- Subject files, 1885 -- 1994; UA010.001; 13.0 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  These subject files were collected by Russell Miller while preparing his history of Tufts University, Light on the Hill.
  Miller organized his materials by subject without regard for original order. No attempt has been made to recreate the original order of these materials.
  This series contains files from the alumni association, correspondence from the office of the dean, the office of the president, the board of trustees, information about the class of 1898, course materials, faculty information, several folders dealing with fundraising, the fiftieth anniversary, grounds and buildings, the medical honorary society, the HSDB, personnel, two folders of photos of early faculty. More than half the series is comprised of information dealing with the TCCHAP (the Tufts Comprehensive Community Health Action Program). This collection contains information of various committees, family support groups and activities, financing, various projects, budget, childcare, information about the Columbia Point Outreach Center and the outreach center in Mound Bayou.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Administrative committee, 1929 -- 1935; UA010.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Admissions, 1935 -- 1971; UA010.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Alpha epsilon iota, 1917; UA010.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Alumni association, 1939 -- 1976; UA010.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Alumni-dean's letters, 1946 -- 1965; UA010.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Alumni ae-graduates, 1940 -- 1943; UA010.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Centennial celebration, 1993; UA010.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Class activities, 1908 -- 1941; UA010.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Class of 1898, UA010.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Commonwealth fund, 1930 -- 1977; UA010.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (board of trustees), 1885 -- 1899; UA010.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (office of the president), 1918 -- 1924; UA010.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (office of the president), 1925 -- 1930; UA010.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence (office of the president), 1931 -- 1935; UA010.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence., 1936 -- 1954; UA010.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1955 -- 1965; UA010.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1966 -- 1967; UA010.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1968; UA010.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1969; UA010.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1970; UA010.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence (office of the president), 1971; UA010.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1972; UA010.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1973 -- 1974; UA010.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Courses-programs, 1918 -- 1973; UA010.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Dedication of medical/dental building, 1951; UA010.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Faculty, 1916 -- 1971; UA010.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Faculty meetings, 1930 -- 1939; UA010.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Fund raising, 1937 -- 1950; UA010.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Fund raising, 1937 -- 1971; UA010.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - Fund raising committee, 1944 -- 1947; UA010.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - Fund raising -- correspondance, 1939 -- 1942; UA010.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - Fund raising -- contributors, 1939 -- 1942; UA010.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - Fund raising -- delinquents, 1939 -- 1941; UA010.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - Fund raising development fund, 1930 -- 1939; UA010.001.005.00006 (Box 5)
  - Fund raising development fund, 1940 -- 1944; UA010.001.005.00007 (Box 5)
  - Fund raising -- financial items, 1938 -- 1944; UA010.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - Fund raising, 1930 -- 1944; UA010.001.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - Fund raising -- golden book, 1950; UA010.001.006.00003 (Box 6)
  - Fund raising -- Godfrey H. Hyams trust, 1939 -- 1949; UA010.001.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - Fund raising -- organization of campaign, 1938 -- 1950; UA010.001.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - Fund raising -- medical fund, 1930 -- 1945; UA010.001.006.00006 (Box 6)
  - Fund raising -- memorial funds, 1940 -- 1941; UA010.001.006.00007 (Box 6)
  - Fund raising -- Morrison Hyman, 1941 -- 1951; UA010.001.006.00008 (Box 6)
  - Fund raising -- new building, 1944; UA010.001.006.00009 (Box 6)
  - Fund raising -- planning committee, 1945 -- 1946; UA010.001.006.00010 (Box 6)
  - Fund raising report -- medical school fund, 1939 -- 1994; UA010.001.006.00011 (Box 6)
  - Fund raising -- student solicitation, 1939 -- 1940; UA010.001.007.00001 (Box 7)
  - Fund raising -- steering committee, 1939 -- 1940; UA010.001.007.00002 (Box 7)
  - Fund raising -- special gifts, 1937 -- 1941; UA010.001.007.00003 (Box 7)
  - Fund raising -- Tufts trustees, 1939 -- 1942; UA010.001.007.00004 (Box 7)
  - Fiftieth anniversary, 1943; UA010.001.007.00005 (Box 7)
  - Grounds and buildings, 1932 -- 1963; UA010.001.007.00006 (Box 7)
  - Grounds and buildings -- buildings committee, 1947; UA010.001.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - Grounds and buildings -- Dennison House, 1942, UA010.001.008.00002 (Box 8)
  - Grounds and buildings -- printed matter, photos, UA010.001.008.00003 (Box 8)
  - History and historical society, 1939 -- 1946; UA010.001.008.00004 (Box 8)
  - Health sciences education building, UA010.001.008.00005 (Box 8)
  - Health sciences education building, 1982; UA010.001.008.00006 (Box 8)
  - HSEB planning committee reports and minutes (1), 1982; UA010.001.008.00007 (Box 8)
  - HSEB planning committee reports and minutes (2), 1982; UA010.001.008.00008 (Box 8)
  - HSEB program concept and project criteria, 1982; UA010.001.008.00009 (Box 8)
  - HSEB publication concepts, 1982; UA010.001.008.00010 (Box 8)
  - HSEB report of the clinical library sites committee (1), 1982; UA010.001.008.00011 (Box 8)
  - HSEB report of the clinical library sites committee (2), 1982; UA010.001.009.00001 (Box 9)
  - HSEB reprints (1), 1982; UA010.001.009.00002 (Box 9)
  - HSEB reprints (2), 1982; UA010.001.009.00003 (Box 9)
  - HSEB workbook, 1982; UA010.001.009.00004 (Box 9)
  - Information management agenda, 1980; UA010.001.009.00005 (Box 9)
  - Lemul Shattuck hospital, 1970; UA010.001.009.00006 (Box 9)
  - Medical honorary society, 1938 -- 1939; UA010.001.009.00007 (Box 9)
  - National board results, highest marks, 1929 -- 1938; UA010.001.009.00008 (Box 9)
  - Needs and objectives for the medical and dental schools, 1942; UA010.001.009.00009 (Box 9)
  - Office of economic opportunity, 1969 -- 1971; UA010.001.009.00010 (Box 9)
  - Personnel, 1911 -- 1927; UA010.001.010.00001 (Box 10)
  - Phi chi, 1920; UA010.001.010.00002 (Box 10)
  - Photos (1), UA010.001.010.00003 (Box 10)
  - Photos (2), UA010.001.010.00004 (Box 10)
  - Radioisotope committee, 1955 -- 1961; UA010.001.010.00005 (Box 10)
  - Report to the governor of Mass. regarding the U. of Mass. mediacal school, 1969; UA010.001.010.00006 (Box 10)
  - Student body-student government, 1930 -- 1933; UA010.001.010.00007 (Box 10)
  - TCCHAP, ABCD, 1964 -- 1966; UA010.001.010.00008 (Box 10)
  - TCCHAP, ABCD, 1968; UA010.001.011.00001 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, alert medicare -- report, 1966; UA010.001.011.00002 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, absentee project (1), 1967; UA010.001.011.00003 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, absentee project (2), 1967; UA010.001.011.00004 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, absentee -- tardy program, 1967; UA010.001.011.00005 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, accident control, UA010.001.011.00006 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, accidental injury, UA010.001.011.00007 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, ad hoc committees, 1965; UA010.001.011.00008 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, ad hoc committees, 1966; UA010.001.011.00009 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, ad hoc committees, 1965 -- 1966; UA010.001.011.00010 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, ad hoc educational planning, 1969; UA010.001.011.00011 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, administrative committee, 1970; UA010.001.011.00012 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, administration memos, 1970; UA010.001.011.00013 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, administrative procedures, 1970; UA010.001.011.00014 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, administrative staff meetings, 1967; UA010.001.011.00015 (Box 11)
  - TCCHAP, agency addresses, Columbia Point, 1967; UA010.001.012.00001 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, aging, 1967; UA010.001.012.00002 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, alcoholism, UA010.001.012.00003 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, Alice, 1967; UA010.001.012.00004 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, Ann Stokes, 1967; UA010.001.012.00005 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, annual reports, 1968; UA010.001.012.00006 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, annual reports, 1969 -- 1970; UA010.001.012.00007 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, appointments, 1968; UA010.001.012.00008 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, baider paper, 1967; UA010.001.012.00009 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, babysitters, 1967; UA010.001.012.00010 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, babysitting training, 1967; UA010.001.012.00011 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, BEAM-health association, 1970; UA010.001.012.00012 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, bellanger food buying, 1967; UA010.001.012.00013 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, Berton Fliegel, 1970; UA010.001.012.00014 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, BHA, 1965; UA010.001.012.00015 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, BHA, 1967; UA010.001.012.00016 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, BHA, 1970; UA010.001.012.00017 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, BHA -- housing statistics, 1967; UA010.001.012.00018 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, BHA-CHA referral, 1967; UA010.001.012.00019 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, BHA-CHA referrals, 1967; UA010.001.012.00020 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, booklets, UA010.001.012.00021 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, big brother, 1969; UA010.001.012.00022 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, Bill and Burt, correspondence, 1968; UA010.001.012.00023 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, blacks, 1969; UA010.001.012.00024 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, board of directors, 1966; UA010.001.012.00025 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, budget, 1966; UA010.001.012.00026 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, budget justification, 1967; UA010.001.012.00027 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, business office, CPHC, 1970; UA010.001.012.00028 (Box 12)
  - TCCHAP, camp, 1967; UA010.001.013.00001 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Campbell, 1965 -- 1966; UA010.001.013.00002 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Campbell, Carlson, 1967; UA010.001.013.00003 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, case summaries, UA010.001.013.00004 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, caseload files, 1967; UA010.001.013.00005 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, centaum, 1969; UA010.001.013.00006 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Community Health Association fact sheet, 1967; UA010.001.013.00007 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, job description, 1966; UA010.001.013.00008 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, job description, 1966; UA010.001.013.00009 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Community Health Association log, UA010.001.013.00010 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Community Health Association newsletter, 1967; UA010.001.013.00011 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Community Health Association programs, 1966; UA010.001.013.00012 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Community Health Association quarterly report, 1967; UA010.001.013.00013 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Community Health Association staff, 1967; UA010.001.013.00014 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Community Health Association staff meeting agenda, 1967; UA010.001.013.00015 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Community Health Association staff meetings, 1968; UA010.001.013.00016 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Community Health Association staff memos, 1967; UA010.001.013.00017 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Community Health Association report, October, 1967; UA010.001.013.00018 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, check vouchers, 1968; UA010.001.013.00019 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Chicago NHC meeting, 1967; UA010.001.013.00020 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, child care proposal, 1969; UA010.001.013.00021 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, chronological file, 1966; UA010.001.013.00022 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, circulars, UA010.001.013.00023 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, clinic service reports, 1967; UA010.001.013.00024 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point, 1965 -- 1968; UA010.001.013.00025 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point, July-Decmber, 1969; UA010.001.013.00026 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point, April-June, 1969; UA010.001.013.00027 (Box 13)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point Health Association Training, 1968 -- 1969; UA010.001.014.00001 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point budget, 1970; UA010.001.014.00002 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point, 1970 -- 1973; UA010.001.014.00003 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point APAC, 1967; UA010.001.014.00004 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point apartment guide, UA010.001.014.00005 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point cooperative, UA010.001.014.00006 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point community resources, 1963; UA010.001.014.00007 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point community developent council, 1968; UA010.001.014.00008 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point data collection manual, UA010.001.014.00009 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point fact sheet, 1967; UA010.001.014.00010 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point health association, 1967; UA010.001.014.00011 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point health association, 1968; UA010.001.014.00012 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point interagency, 1970; UA010.001.014.00013 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point opening ceremonies, 1965; UA010.001.014.00014 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point research, 1961; UA010.001.014.00015 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, Columbia Point study, 1961; UA010.001.014.00016 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP communications, 1967; UA010.001.014.00017 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, communications contract, UA010.001.014.00018 (Box 14)
  - TCCHAP, community action program, 1965; UA010.001.015.00001 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, community action studies project, 1964; UA010.001.015.00002 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, community activities, 1967; UA010.001.015.00003 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, community agencies task force, 1969; UA010.001.015.00004 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, community health action, 1968; UA010.001.015.00005 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, community health education, 1969; UA010.001.015.00006 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, community health nurse, UA010.001.015.00007 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, community health news, 1967; UA010.001.015.00008 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, community relations health educator, board of directors, 1966; UA010.001.015.00009 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, comparison cards, 1965; UA010.001.015.00010 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, comprehensive health planning, 1967; UA010.001.015.00011 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, conferences out of town, 1967; UA010.001.015.00012 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, consultants, 1967; UA010.001.015.00013 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, correspondence, 1967; UA010.001.015.00014 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, correspondence training program, 1968; UA010.001.015.00015 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, correspondence, 1967; UA010.001.015.00016 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, Count Gibson, 1967; UA010.001.015.00017 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, CPPC (Columbia Point Community Center), 1967; UA010.001.015.00018 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, CPCC (Columbia Point Community Center) refferal, 1967; UA010.001.015.00019 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, CPCC (Columbia Point Community Center) skill training, 1967; UA010.001.015.00020 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, CPDC (Columbia Point Community Development Council), 1968; UA010.001.015.00021 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, CPDC (Columbia Point Community Development Council), 1965; UA010.001.015.00022 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, CPDC (Columbia Point Community Developent Council), 1968; UA010.001.015.00023 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, CPDC (Columbia Point Health Association), 1967; UA010.001.015.00024 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, CPDC (Columbia Point Health Association), 1968; UA010.001.015.00025 (Box 15)
  - TCCHAP, CPHA (Columbia Point Health Association), 1967; UA010.001.016.00001 (Box 16)
  - TCCHAP, CPHA (Columbia Point Health Association board of directors, 1966; UA010.001.016.00002 (Box 16)
  - TCCHAP, CPHA-OEO budget, 1968 -- 1969; UA010.001.016.00003 (Box 16)
  - TCCHAP, CPHC (Columbia Point health center) evaluation, 1970; UA010.001.016.00004 (Box 16)
  - TCCHAP, CPHC (Columbia Point health center) guide, 1967; UA010.001.016.00005 (Box 16)